AKARSH H P

INDIA 560049 ◆ 8970473432 ◆ akarsh77prakash@gmail.com ◆ WWW: Bold Profile

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An Four year experienced mechanical engineer with a distinctive background in design and project management in the area of rubber components, tools and dies, as well as extensive knowledge of solid works, UGNX and Autocad. Committed to providing a top notch and accurate work with great excellence, Consistently completing all the projects within the budget and timeline provided.

SKILLS

- 3D Modelling
- Drafting
- Change Board
- Vendor Management
- Obsolescence management
- SAP
- Product Configurationn
- GD&T
- PFMEA and DFMEA

- Prototyping
- New part development
- Projet Management
- Management of Bill of Material
- PPAP and APQP
- Engineering change configuration
- Product life cycle Management
- Team Center
- Quality Assurance

WORK HISTORY

Engineering Change Management and Product Configuration, 05/2022 - Current **Stratosphere It Service Pvt Ltd (at Genral Motors)** – Bengaluru, India

- Managed for Bill of material for corporate common components such switch assemblies, seats and semiconductor parts.
- Managed change configuration of corporate common components according to system driven by organization.
- Created and assigned new part numbers for automobile parts, Reviewed and Approved drawings through Team Center.
- Extensively worked on ECR and ECN process for BOM management.
- Ensured CFT being notified about the change configuration and brought down them into a distribution.
- Ensured P-release activities of programs are build intact within required timeline.
- Ensured all the design release are intact in manufacturing plant.
- Drafted documentation detailing design requirements and technical specifications

New Product Development Engineer, 08/2020 - 04/2022

SRP Synthetic Rubber Products – Bengaluru, India

- Designed and lead design reviews for new product development process from concept through production.
- Identified the necessary capital requirements for new design.
- Ensured new part development design met customer requirements and managed to achieve the results within the budget allocation.
- Ensured project is completed within the timeline and monitored through APQP.
- Assured customer with quality parts and submitted PPAP reports.
- Tested materials with respect to specifications provided ie, Hardness, tensile, ash content and aging test.
- Negotiated with vendors and manufacturers on pricing, services and scheduled shipping windows.
- Demonstrated creativity and resourcefulness through the development of innovative solutions.
- Identified changes in project scope and modified job schedule accordingly.
- Traveled to manufacturing facilities to evaluate product creation and point out potential issues.

Design Engineer, 01/2020 - 08/2020

Genx Tools - Bengaluru, India

- Designed and Developed rubber moulding tools.
- Developed new designes for prototypes.
- Developed new design for reducing flash marks on the rubber components.
- Drafted documentation detailing design requirements and technical specifications.
- Collaborated with other departments to facilitate successful project completion.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to conceptualize and refine product concepts.
- Evaluated project feasibility based on material, equipment and labor expenses.

	EDUCATION
--	-----------

Master Of Business Administration: Manufacturing Management And Analytics, Expected in 01/2024 IIM Trichy - Trichy

Bachelor Of Engineering: Mechanical Engineering, 06/2019

Dayananda Sagar Academy of Technology And Management - Bengaluru

• Member of Way for life (Backward Children Welfare)

 TO	TAD	ATT	ONI
 HU	LAK	A I I	\cup

I here by declare that the above mentioned information is correct upto my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above mentioned particulars.